-=TLF字幕组=- 荣誉出品
翻译：Lydia萌
翻译：versus
翻译：苏叶
君临
King's Landing
翻译：LordVader
翻译：Hello_Agnes
校对：LordVader
特效：飞翔的鸡
龙石岛
DragonStone
恐怖堡
Dreadfort
临冬城
WinterFell
绝境长城
The Wall
弥林
Meereen
根据乔治·R·R·马丁著《冰与火之歌》改编
权利的游戏
第四季   第二集
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
电视剧编剧
戴维·贝尼奥夫 & D·B·威斯
导演
阿历克斯·格瑞弗斯
奴隶解放者
You did this. You did this!
是你干的，是你干的！
- We have to leave. - Take him! Take him!
- 我们必须走了
<i>- 抓住他！抓住他！</i>
Where is his wife?
他妻子在哪？
Where's Sansa?
珊莎在哪？
Find her. Bar the gates of the city.
找到她，封锁城门
Seize every ship in the harbor.
<i>扣留港口里所有的船</i>
- Where is she?! - No one leaves the capital!
- 她在哪？！
- 谁都不许离开王都！
No one!
<i>不许！</i>
- Get in. - Where are we going?
- 上来吧
- 我们要去哪？
Somewhere safe.
安全的地方
Up you go, my lady.
上去吧，夫人
You'll be fine.
你会没事的
You're stronger than you know.
你比自己想象得坚强
- Lord Baelish? - Petyr.
- 贝里席大人？
- 叫我培提尔
Are you hurt, my lady?
你受伤了吗，夫人？
Good. Good.
没事就好
I'm sure you've had quite a fright. Rest easy.
你肯定吓坏了，好好休息吧
- The worst is past. - Lord Baelish.
- 最糟糕的已经过去了
<i>- 贝里席大人</i>
I promised I'd get her to you safely.
<i>我保证把她安全带给你了</i>
Softly, my friend.
小点声，朋友
Voices carry over water.
水会传播声音
I should get back before someone thinks to look for me.
我得在引人注意前回去
First you'll want your pay.
要先拿报酬
- 10,000 was it? - 10,000.
- 是1万吗？
- 1万
Wait!
等等！
Shh.
<i>嘘</i>
You don't want the queen to hear, do you?
你不想让太后听见吧？
1,000 gold cloaks are searching for you.
一千个金袍子正在找你呢
And if they found you,
如果他们找到你了
how do you think they would punish the girl who murdered the king?
你觉得他们会怎样惩罚谋杀国王的女孩呢？
- I didn't murder anyone. - I know. I know.
- 我没有谋杀任何人
- 我知道，我知道
But you must admit it looks suspicious.
但你必须承认你很有嫌疑
The king who executed your father,
国王处决了你父亲
who tormented you for years,
折磨了你数年
and you fled the scene of his murder.
而且你从他的被害现场逃了
Why did you kill him?
你为什么杀他？
Because he was a drunk and a fool
因为他喝多了，还是个弄臣
and I don't trust drunk fools.
我不信任喝多的弄臣
He saved me.
他救了我
Saved you? My lady, he followed my orders.
救你？夫人，他只是听从我的命令
Every one of them. And he did it all for gold.
一切都是我的命令，他只为了金子
Money buys a man's silence for a time.
<i>钱能让人暂时保密</i>
A bolt in the heart buys it forever.
一箭穿心才能让人永远闭嘴
He was helping me because I saved his life.
他帮我是因为我救过他的命
Yes, and he gave you a priceless necklace
是的，然后他送了你一条珍贵的项链
that once belonged to his grandmother.
这项链曾经属于他祖母
The last legacy of House Hollard.
霍拉德家族最后的遗物
I had it made a few weeks ago.
我几星期前找人做的
What did I once tell you about the capital?
我曾经告诉过你什么？
We're all liars here.
都城里都是骗子
Come, my lady.
来吧，夫人
I know you've had a difficult day.
我知道你今天不容易
But you're safe now.
但现在你安全了
I promise you that.
我保证
You're safe with me
跟我在一起，你会安全
and sailing home.
驶向家乡
So am I the queen?
那我是王后吗？
More than you were with Renly.
比跟蓝礼在一起要强
Less than you would have been if Joffrey had done you the courtesy
但乔佛里还没完成合房礼
of consummating the marriage before dying.
就死了，还差点意思
In any case, this would not be an opportune moment
不管怎样，此时都不适合
to press the issue.
追问此事
Clawing at his own throat,
抓着自己的喉咙
looking to his mother to make it stop-- it was horrible.
祈求母亲能救他…真是可怕
The world is overflowing with horrible things.
这世上充溢着可怕之事
But they're all a tray of cakes next to death.
但跟死亡相比都不值一提
They brought me your grandfather's body when he died, you know?
知道吗，你爷爷死的时候，他们带我去他的尸体旁
Made me look at it.
强迫我去看
What was it like?
那是什么样的？
They took me to the Great Hall and there he was.
他们带我去大厅，他就在那
The man I'd married
我委身的男人
and suffered to father my children.
我孩子们的父亲
A great doughy lump I'd sat next to
在数不清的晚宴和无聊的聚会上
at endless dinners and tedious gatherings.
我都坐在他身旁
There he was...
他就在那…
lying on a table.
横在桌子上
One of my husbands preferred the company of men
我的丈夫们，一个喜欢男人
and was stabbed through the heart.
被一剑刺穿心脏
Another was happiest torturing animals
另一个热衷折磨动物
and was poisoned at our wedding feast.
在婚宴上被毒死
- I must be cursed. - Nonsense.
- 我肯定是被诅咒了
- 胡说
Your circumstances have improved markedly.
你的境况明显得到改善
You may not have enjoyed watching him die,
也许你不喜欢看他死掉
but you enjoyed it more than you would have enjoyed
但我保证，你会更不喜欢
being married to him, I can promise you that.
嫁给他之后的日子
But I would have been the queen.
但我本可以成为王后
Our alliance with the Lannisters
我们跟兰尼斯特保持联姻
remains every bit as necessary to them
对我们来说有多不愉快
as it is unpleasant for us.
对他们来说就有多重要
You did wonderful work on Joffrey.
你对乔佛里做得很好
The next one should be easier.
下一个应该会容易些
Your brother is dead.
<i>你哥哥死了</i>
Do you know what that means?
你知道那意味着什么吗？
I'm not trying to trick you.
我没在逗你
It means I'll become king.
这意味着我将成为国王
Yes, you will become king.
是的，你会成为国王
What kind of king do you think you'll be?
你认为你会成为哪种国王？
A good king?
好国王？
Mm, I think so as well.
嗯，我也这么认为
You've got the right temperament for it.
你的秉性很适合
But what makes a good king? Hmm?
<i>但怎样才能成为好国王？嗯？</i>
What is a good king's single most important quality?
好国王最重要的一条品质是什么？
This is hardly the place or the time.
此时此地不该谈这个
Holiness?
圣洁？
Baelor the Blessed was holy.
<i>“受神祝福的”贝勒就很圣洁</i>
And pious.
也很虔诚
He built this sept.
他修建了这座圣堂
He also named a six-year-old boy high septon
他还任命一个六岁大的男孩为总主教
because he thought the boy could work miracles.
因为他相信这个男孩能施行神迹
He ended up fasting himself into an early grave
他早早进了坟墓
because food was of this world
因为这个世界的食物
and this world was sinful.
以及这个世界都有罪
Justice.
公正
A good king must be just.
好国王必须要公正
Orys I was just.
奥里斯一世就很公正
Everyone applauded his reforms.
人人赞赏他的改革
Nobles and commoners alike.
贵族与百姓平等
But he wasn't just for long.
但他没公正多久
He was murdered in his sleep
改革不到一年，他在睡梦中
after less than a year by his own brother.
被他的亲兄弟杀死了
Was that truly just of him?
弃自己的国民于恶魔之手
To abandon his subjects to an evil
只因自己太轻易受其蒙蔽
that he was too gullible to recognize?
这样真的公正吗？
- No. - No.
- 不
- What about strength? - Yes.
- 那强壮呢？
- 是啊
Strength.
强壮
King Robert was strong.
劳勃国王就很强壮
He won the rebellion
他赢了篡夺者战争
and crushed the Targaryen dynasty.
推翻了坦格利安王朝
And he attended three small council meetings
而且17年来他只参加过三次…
in 17 years.
御前议会
He spent his time whoring and hunting and drinking
<i>他荒度终日，嫖娼、打猎、酗酒</i>
until the last two killed him.
直到最后死于打猎和酗酒
So, we have a man who starves himself to death,
<i>那么，一个绝食而死</i>
a man who lets his own brother murder him,
一个被兄弟谋杀
and a man who thinks that winning and ruling are the same thing.
一个自认为赢天下与治天下是一回事
What do they all lack?
他们都缺少什么？
- Wisdom. - Yes!
- 智慧
- 是的！
Wisdom is what makes a good king.
有智慧，才能成为好国王
Yes.
是的
But what is wisdom? Hmm?
但什么是智慧？嗯？
A house with great wealth and fertile lands
<i>一个家财富裕土地富饶的家族</i>
asks you for your protection
<i>向你寻求庇护</i>
against another house with a strong navy
反抗另一个海军强大
that could one day oppose you.
且可能谋反的家族
How do you know which choice is wise and which isn't?
你怎样知道何为明智之选？
You've any experience of treasuries and granaries
你有任何关于管理国库粮仓
or shipyards and soldiers?
<i>或统率船只和士兵的经验吗？</i>
- No. - No. Of course not.
- 没有
- <i>没有，当然没有</i>
A wise king knows what he knows and what he doesn't.
明智的国王要知道自己懂什么，不懂什么
You're young.
你还年轻
A wise young king listens to his counselors
<i>明智又年轻的国王就要听从参事</i>
and heeds their advice until he comes of age.
接受他们的意见直到长大
And the wisest kings
最明智的国王
continue to listen to them long afterwards.
会在长大后继续听取意见
Your brother was not a wise king.
你哥哥不是明智的国王
Your brother was not a good king.
<i>你哥哥不是好国王</i>
If he had been,
<i>如果他是好国王</i>
perhaps he'd still be alive.
也许就不会死
Now, as the king, you will have to marry.
现在，作为国王，你必须成婚
Do you understand why?
你明白为什么吗？
A king needs a queen.
<i>国王需要有王后</i>
Yes, but why?
<i>是的，但是为什么呢？</i>
To further the family line.
为了延续家族血脉
- Do you know how that happens? - Yes.
- <i>你知道怎样做吗？</i>
- 知道
Yes, but has anyone explained the details to you?
我是说有人跟你解释过细节吗？
I don't think so.
我认为没有
It's all relatively straightforward.
这个要更直接简单
- How are you? - I'm all right.
- 你还好吗？
- 我没事
You are. You will be.
你没事，以后也不会有事
I'll see to that.
我向你保证
Please give the queen a moment alone with her son.
请让太后与她儿子独处一会儿
- Yes, my lord. - All of you.
- 是的，大人
- 所有人都下去
It was Tyrion.
是提利昂
He killed him.
他杀了他
He told me he would.
他告诉过我他会杀他
"A day will come when you think you are safe and happy
“终有一天，当你感觉安全而幸福的时候”
and your joy will turn to ashes in your mouth."
“你的喜悦会化为口中的灰烬”
That's what he said to me.
这是他对我说的
You saw it.
你看到了
You saw Joff point at him just before he--
你看到小乔指着他，就在他…
I don't know what I saw.
我不知道看见了什么
Avenge him.
为他报仇
Avenge our son.
为我们的儿子报仇
Kill Tyrion.
杀了提利昂
Tyrion's my brother.
提利昂是我的弟弟
Our brother.
<i>我们的弟弟</i>
There'll be a trial. We'll get to the truth of what happened.
会有审判的，我们会得到事情的真相
I don't want a trial.
我不想要审判
He'll squirm his way to freedom given the chance.
只要一有机会他就会溜之大吉
I want him dead.
我要他死
Please, Jaime.
求你了，詹姆
You have to.
你必须杀他
He was our son.
他是我们的儿子
Our baby boy.
我们的宝贝儿子
You're a hateful woman.
你是个心怀仇恨的女人
Why have the gods made me love a hateful woman?
为什么诸神要让我爱上一个心怀仇恨的女人？
Jaime, not here, please.
詹姆，不要在这，求你
Please.
求你
Stop it.
住手
- Stop it. Stop. - No.
- 住手，住手
- 不
Stop it. Stop.
住手，住手
Stop.
住手
Stop. It's not right.
住手，这样不对
It's not right. It's not right.
这样不对，这样不对
I don't care.
我不在乎
- Don't. - I don't care.
- 不要
- 我不在乎
- Don't. Jaime, don't. - I don't care.
- 不要，詹姆，不要
- 我不在乎
Gonna rain soon.
很快要下雨了
Where are we?
这是哪？
Near Fairmarket, I think.
我觉得是美人市集附近
You think?
你觉得？
You don't have a map?
你没有地图吗？
- No, I don't have a map. - Maybe we should get one.
- <i>我没有地图</i>
- 也许我们该弄一个
Just point out the next map shop you see and I'll buy you one.
下次看到地图商店告诉我，我给你买
How far is it to the Eyrie?
离鹰巢城还有多远？
Far.
很远
And you're sure we're going the right way?
你确定我们没走错路？
Believe me, girl, I want you there as soon as I can.
相信我，姑娘，我愿意尽快把你送到
Get my gold, be on my way.
拿上我的金子，继续上路
- On your way where? - Why do you care?
- 上哪的路？
- 关你什么事？
Might book passage across the Narrow Sea.
也许会乘船过狭海
Fight as a sellsword.
<i>当个雇佣兵</i>
Second Sons, could be. Seems like a good fit for me.
也许加入次子团，感觉挺适合我
I'd like to see Braavos one day.
我希望有一天能去布拉佛斯
Why Braavos?
为什么？
I have friends there.
有朋友在那
I doubt it.
我怀疑
Seven blessings to you.
愿七神保佑你
What do you want?
你想干什么？
What do I want? This is my land.
我想干什么？这是我的地
If I'm standing on it, it's my land.
我站的地方，就是我的地
We were just watering the horses. We'll be on our way.
我们只是在给马喂水，很快就离开
Forgive my father.
请原谅我父亲
He was wounded fighting in the war.
<i>他去打仗的时候受了伤</i>
Our cottage burned down while he was gone and my mother with it.
他离开的时候，房子被烧了，妈妈在里面
He's never been the same.
之后他就变了个人
Which house did he fight for?
他为哪个家族打仗？
The Tullys of Riverrun.
奔流城的徒利家族
There's a storm coming.
快下暴雨了
You'll be wanting a roof tonight.
<i>你们今晚来我家避避吧</i>
There's fresh hay in the barn.
<i>牲口棚里有新鲜牧草</i>
And Sally here makes rabbit stew just like her mom used to do.
这是萨丽，她炖的兔肉汤跟她妈妈炖的一样美味
We don't have much, but any man that bled
虽然不多，但只要是为徒利家族流血的
for House Tully is welcome to it.
我们都欢迎
We ask the Father to judge us with mercy
我们向天父祈求仁慈的裁决
accepting our human frailty.
接纳我们人类的脆弱
We ask the Mother to bless our crops
我们向圣母祈求庄稼的保护
so we may feed ourselves and all who come to our door.
使我们能自给自足也能宴请客人
We ask the Warrior to give us courage
我们向战士祈求勇气
in these days of strife and turmoil.
在这争斗动荡的日子里
We ask the Maiden to protect Sally's virtue
我们向少女祈求保护萨莉的贞洁
to keep her from the clutches of depravity.
让她远离堕落的魔掌
You got to do all seven of the fuckers?
你要对七个神经病都来一遍？
Father!
爸！
We ask the Smith to strengthen our hands
我们向铁匠祈求强力的双手和脊背
and our backs so we may finish the work required of us.
使我们的能完成需要的工作
We ask the Crone to guide us on our journey from darkness to darkness.
我们向老妪祈求指引，以在黑暗中完成旅程
And we ask the Stranger not to kill us
我们亦向陌客祈求
in our beds tonight for no damn reason at all.
不要在今夜将我们杀死在床上，没有任何该死的原因
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
Really good.
很棒
- Did you fight at the Twins? - Call that a fight?
- 你在孪河城打过仗
- 你把那称为打仗？
Slaughtering livestock more like.
更像是宰杀牲口
The Red Wedding they're calling it.
他们称之为血婚
Walder Frey committed sacrilege that day.
瓦德·佛雷在那天做了冒渎之事
He shared bread and salt with the Starks. He offered them guest right.
他用面包和盐巴招待了史塔克家族，给了他们客人的礼遇
Guest right don't mean much anymore.
待客之道现在没有任何意义
It means something to me.
对我来说还是有的
The gods will have their vengeance.
诸神会报复他们的
Frey will burn in the seventh hell for what he did.
由于佛雷的所作作为，他会在七层地狱被烧死
Things were different when Hoster Tully ruled the Riverlands.
霍斯特·徒利主政污泥厅的时候可不一样
We had good years and bad years, same as anyone.
和其他人一样，我们的日子时好时坏
But we were safe. Now with the Freys,
但总是很安全，现在佛雷来了
raiders come plundering, steal our food, steal our silver.
歹徒总来掠夺，偷我们的食物和银子
I was gonna send Sally north to stay with my brother,
我本想把萨莉送去北方，我母亲那里
but the north's no better. The whole country's gone sour.
但北方也没好到哪儿去，整个国家都要完了
You got any ale?
你有麦酒没有
Afraid not.
恐怕没有
How can a man not keep ale in his home?
一个男人家里怎么能没有麦酒呢？
You look like you could really swing that sword.
你看起来真的能挥舞那把剑
A real warrior with proper training.
一个真的战士，训练有素
Those raiders wouldn't stand a chance against you.
那些歹徒在你面前没有机会
How would it be if you stayed on till the new moon?
你在这待到新月怎么样
I could use a man to help with the farmwork.
我就能有人帮忙干干农活
Sally does what she can,
萨莉能做一些事
but she can't lift a bale of hay.
但她拿不起干草包
And if any thieves came looking for easy pickings,
我敢打赌，如果有小偷敢来偷东西
one look at you, I'd bet they'd run the other way.
看到你就会落荒而逃
Meaning no offense.
我无意冒犯
What'll you pay?
不过，你给多少钱？
I don't have much.
我钱不多
But I have hidden a bit of silver from the bandits.
但我藏了点银子没让强盗拿走
Fair wages for fair work?
干多少活就拿多少钱？
Fair wages for fair work.
干多少活就拿多少钱
- What did you do?! - Get your horse saddled.
- 你做了什么？
- 给你的马上鞍
- You told me you weren't a thief. - I wasn't.
- 你告诉过我你不是小偷
- 原来不是
He took us in. He fed us and you--
他收留我们，他给我们食物，你居然…
Aye, he took us in. He's a good man
是，他收留我们了，他是个好人
and his daughter makes a nice stew.
他女儿还烧得一手好菜
And they'll both be dead come winter.
然后凛冬来的时候他们都得死
- You don't know that. - I do know it.
- 你怎么知道
- 我就知道！
He's weak. He can't protect himself.
他软弱到无法保护自己
They'll both be dead come winter.
冬天一来，他俩都会死
Dead men don't need silver.
死人不需要银子
You're the worst shit in the Seven Kingdoms.
你是七国里最臭的狗屎
There's plenty worse than me.
比我差的大有人在
I just understand the way things are.
我只是面对现实
How many Starks they got to behead before you figure it out?
多少史塔克家族的人在你不知道的时候就人头落地了？
Raper. Raper.
强奸犯，又一个强奸犯
Horse thief.
盗马贼
Ninth born son.
第九子
Raper.
还是强奸犯
Thief. Thief and raper.
小偷，小偷兼强奸犯
There he is, Sam the Slayer.
你来了，杀手山姆
Going to visit your wildling whore?
找你的野人妓女？
- She's not a whore. - No?
- 她不是妓女
- 不是吗？
Maybe I'll give her a copper tonight and find out.
或许我晚上给点钱就知道了
They all think I'm lying.
他们都觉得我在说谎
About what?
说什么谎？
Killing the white walker.
我杀了异鬼
You're not lying.
你没说谎
I'll never forget the way it screamed.
我不会忘记他们的尖叫声
But you're the only one that saw it.
但你是唯一亲眼目睹的人
And they all think you're just a--
而且他们都觉得你是个…
A what?
什么？
Well, a wildling.
呃，一个野人
My father hated that word.
我爸不喜欢那个词
It's not a very nice word, I suppose.
我觉得这个词不是很好
I don't know.
我不知道
It makes me sound a bit dangerous, doesn't it?
这让我听起来有点危险，对吗？
So...
这个…
are you all right?
你还好吧？
No one bothering you?
没有人骚扰你吧？
I get a lot of looks.
各种眼神
I hear them making their jokes.
我听到他们开我玩笑
But no one's touched me if that's what you mean.
但如果你的意思是摸我的话，那没有
I worry about it sometimes.
有的时候我很担心
All the time.
一直很担心
Why do you worry about it?
为什么呢？
100 men, one woman.
100个男人，一个女人
They've got other things to think about.
他们有别的事情要考虑
That's the only thing they think about.
他们只想这一件事情
- You're being silly. - I'm not being silly.
- 犯傻
- 我没有
There's 100 men lying awake at night picturing you.
有100个男人晚上不睡觉，就在脑海里想着你
What about you?
那你呢？
What about me?
我？
Gilly?
吉莉
I worry about you.
我担心你
Thank you.
谢谢你
For what?
谢什么？
For worrying about me.
谢谢你担心我
I don't know if you're safe here.
我不知道你在这里是否安全
They're my brothers,
他们是我的兄弟
but some of them were thieves before they came here.
但在来这里之前，有些人是小偷
Some of them were rapers.
有些人是强奸犯
You saw what they did at your father's keep.
你看到了他们对你父亲的东西做了什么
So what are you saying?
所以你想说什么？
Maybe you'd be safer in Mole's Town.
在鼹鼠村你可能更安全些
Are you bored of me?
你讨厌我了是吗？
Bored of you?
讨厌你？
I...
我…
I want to protect you.
我想要保护你
I'll get these to Hobb.
我把这些拿给哈布
Keep an eye on little Sam.
照顾好小山姆
Your Grace.
大人
You're a literary man now. What do you make of that?
你现在识字了，说说你的看法
- Joffrey? - The usurper Joffrey Baratheon.
- 乔佛里？
- 乔佛里·拜拉席恩，篡位者
I said those words when I  tossed a leech into the fire.
我说这话的时候
A leech filled with bastard blood.
正把一只水蛭扔进火里
A bastard you set free.
它吸饱了血，你放走的私生子的血
I am now faced with a great opportunity
现在我有个大好机会
and I am powerless to take advantage of it.
但我的力量不足以驾驭它
I will find you an army, Your Grace.
大人我会找一只军队给您的
- I've been working day and night-- - What progress have you made?
- 我夜以继日的努力
- 进度如何呢？
I've rallied House Peasebury to your cause.
我已经把比兹伯利家族召集到您的麾下
House Peasebury.
比兹伯利
- House Musgood. - House Musgood.
- 穆斯古德家族
- 穆斯古德
- And House Haigh. - House Haigh.
- 还有海伊家族
- 海伊
They don't have enough men between them to raid a pantry.
他们那点兵打个储藏间都不够用
Westeros is not the world, Your Grace.
陛下，维斯洛特不是世界的全部
We need to look east for ships and men.
我们需要往东边寻找船只和军队
10,000 skilled soldiers fight for the Golden Company.
黄金团有一万名训练有素的士兵
- The Golden Company? - They've never broken a contract.
- 黄金团？
- 他们从不背叛合约
They're sellswords.
他们可是雇佣兵
We're willing to use blood magic to put you on the throne,
我们可以用血魔法把你送上王座
but we're not willing to pay men to fight?
却不可以雇佣兵团打仗？
Now the Red Woman's magic is real.
现在那个红发女人的魔法也许是真的
Her visions and prophecies may be, too,
可能她的异象和预言也是
but I've never heard of visions and prophecies winning a war.
但我从没听过异象和预言能赢得战争
Soldiers win wars. Soldiers on the ground.
是士兵们，站在地上的士兵们
It's dirty on the ground.
站在地上的肮脏的士兵们，赢得战争
We don't have any gold.
但我们没有金子
Not yet.
暂时还没有
If I do not press my claim,
如果我不强调…
my claim will be forgotten.
我的要求就会被忘记
I will not become a page in someone else's history book.
不会在别人的史书里留下痕迹
I'm running out of time, Ser Davos.
我没时间了，戴佛斯爵士
Which means you're running out of time.
意味着你也没时间了
You're late.
你迟到了
I'm sorry, Princess.
对不起，公主
I thought you weren't coming.
我以为你不来了
The Hand of the King doesn't have much leisure time.
国王之手空闲时间不多啊
You won't be a very good Hand if you see the word
你要是把骑士读成马奇士
knight and say "ka-nigit."
就不会成为好的国王之手
That happened once, weeks ago.
有过一次，一周前
You're your father's daughter, no mistake.
你真是你父亲的女儿
Bloody relentless, the both of you.
都那么冷酷无情
It's a new one today. Lots of tricky words.
今天是新的，很多难词
But I think you can manage.
但是我就觉得你能做好
You'll never read well if you move your lips.
默读你永远都读不好
That's how children do it.
小孩就是那样的
"The Life and Adventures of Elyo Grivas
《布拉佛斯的赏金猎人…
First Sword of Braavos."
…伊里欧·吉瓦斯的一生和历险》
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
I like this one. It's full of sword fights and pirates.
我喜欢这本，里面有很多战斗和海盗
You were a pirate once.
你以前也是海盗
No, I was never a pirate. I was a smuggler.
不，我从来不是海盗，我是走私犯
What's the difference?
有什么区别？
Well, if you're a famous smuggler,
嗯，你要是个有名的走私犯
you're not doing it right.
那就不太妙
My father says a criminal is a criminal.
我父亲说，罪犯就是罪犯
Your father lacks an appreciation
你父亲不太会欣赏
of the finer points of bad behavior.
不良行为中的闪光点
So do the Braavosi.
布拉佛斯人也是
- You've sailed to Braavos? - Of course.
- 你远航过布拉佛斯？
- 当然
Almost got beheaded by a First Sword of Braavos.
差点被个赏金猎人把头砍了
I tried to explain to him
我试图和他解释
the difference between pirates and smugglers,
海盗和走私犯的区别
but he didn't seem any more interested in the distinction than your father.
但是他也没有表现多大兴趣，跟你父亲一样
I suppose if you work for the Iron Bank of Braavos
我觉得如果你为布拉佛斯的铁金库工作
and each one of your gold barges is worth half a kingdom,
那的每一艘驳船都装满足够半个国家的黄金
you tend not to be overly concerned with the kind of distinction--
你也不太会去分辨那些区别…
- What was that for? - I need you to write a message.
- 这是因为什么？
- 我需要你帮我写个信息
You should write it yourself. It's good practice.
你应该自己写，这是个很好的锻炼机会
It's too important for me.
它太重要了
I need a smart person to do it. Go on.
我需要个更聪明的人来做，你来
To the offices of the Iron Bank of Braavos
致布拉佛斯的铁金库的官员们
from Stannis Baratheon the one true king of Westeros.
来自维斯特洛大陆的唯一国王，史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
But that's not you.
那不是你
I need to get their attention.
我需要引起他们的注意
Go on. Write.
继续，写
He's seen some adventures, hasn't he?
他也算见过很多世面了，对吧？
- Precious little thing. - Thank you.
- 可爱的小东西
- 谢谢
- What's his name? - Sam.
- 他叫什么名字？
- 山姆
Lovely.
可爱
That the daddy?
他爸？
No.
不是
Where's the daddy?
他爸呢？
He's dead.
死了
Oh. Where you from?
哦，你打哪来？
North of here.
北边
North of here?
北边？
You a fucking wildling?
你是个野人？
- Only room and board? - That's right.
- 只包食宿？
- 对
She'll clean and cook
她可以打扫，做饭
and look after the other girls' babies.
照顾别的女孩的孩子
Could find other work for her, too.
她还可以做别的
- No other work. - There'd be money.
- 不做别的
- 会有钱的
Give you a piece of it.
开个价吧
No other work.
不做别的
I promise to come back and visit whenever I can.
我保证我一定会来看你的
You'll be safer here.
你在这很安全
Who's gonna protect you at Castle Black? Me?
在黑城堡谁能保护你，我吗？
You protected me north of the Wall.
你在长城以北也保护我了
This is different.
那不一样
They're brothers of the Night's Watch
守夜人是我的兄弟
and I can't just stab them in the back
我不能就那么从背后捅一刀
and I can't run away, which is what we did at Craster's.
然后像在卡斯特那一样逃跑
You have to trust me.
你要相信我
It's for the best.
这样是最好的
Best for you.
对你最好而已
Oh, Gilly.
吉莉…
Please don't.
别这样
Greedy.
好贪心
No?
不要？
I'm sorry. You're lovely,
抱歉，你很迷人
I just never acquired the taste.
我只是从来没有这个爱好
You're calling my beauty an acquired taste?
你说我的美人是个爱好？
That's quite all right, lover. It's more for you.
没事，亲爱的，给你就行了
Your loss.
你的损失
You like them both the same?
你同样喜欢
- Boys and girls? - Does that surprise you?
- 男和女？
- 很意外？
Everyone has a preference.
每个人都有所偏爱
Then everyone is missing half the world's pleasure.
那所有人都错失了世界上另一半美好
The gods made that and it delights me.
<i>神造了那些，让我愉悦</i>
The gods made this
神造了这个
and it delights me.
也让我愉悦
When it comes to war, I fight for Dorne.
在战场上，我为多恩而战
When it comes to love, I don't choose sides.
情事上，我不会选哪边
I hope I have as much stamina when I'm your age.
我希望我到你的年龄的时候也这么有精力
What are you, 25?
你多大，25？
Children.
还是个孩子
Someday, if you're lucky,
有一天，如果你幸运的话
you will wake up and realize you are old.
你会醒来发现自己已经老了
That pretty ass of yours will sag.
你漂亮的屁股会下垂了
Your belly will grow soft and your back will ache in the night
肚皮变软了，后背到了晚上就会疼
and gray hairs will sprout from your ears.
白发会爬到你的耳鬓
No one will want you anymore.
<i>没人想要你了</i>
Make sure you fucked your fill before that day.
在这一天到来之前搞个够吧
Did you?
你呢？
He is a prince of Dorne.
他是多恩的亲王
Girls and boys will line up
姑娘们和小伙子们排着队…
to fuck him till the day he dies.
和他搞，直到他死
They will all have to line up behind you.
他们都得排在你后面
- Prince Oberyn. - Lord Tywin.
- <i>奥柏伦亲王</i>
- 泰温大人
May we have the room?
可以单独谈一下吗？
Call my name if you need me, lover.
需要的时候叫我，爱人
Would you like to sit?
想坐下吗？
No, thank you.
不，谢谢
Some wine?
酒呢？
No, thank you.
<i>不，谢谢</i>
- I'm sorry about your grandson. - Are you?
- 你外孙的事，我很痛心
- 是吗？
I don't believe that a child is responsible for the sins of his father.
我觉得，孩子不该为父亲的罪孽负责
Or his grandfather.
或者祖父辈的
An awful way to die.
死得太惨了
Which way is that?
怎么惨？
Are you interrogating me, Lord Tywin?
你在拷问我吗，泰温大人？
Some believe the king choked.
有人认为国王是噎死的
Some believe the sky is blue because we live
有人认为，天之所以是蓝色是因为我们住在…
inside the eye of a blue-eyed giant.
巨人的蓝色眼睛里
The king was poisoned.
国王是被毒死的
I hear you studied poisons at the Citadel.
我听说你在学城研究过用毒
I did. This is why I know.
是的，所以我知道
Your hatred for my family is rather well known.
你对我们家族的憎恨众所周知
You arrive at the capital, an expert in poisoning,
你一个用毒的行家，来到了都城
some days later my grandson dies of poisoning.
过几天我的外孙就被毒死了
Rather suspicious.
很蹊跷
Why haven't you thrown me in a dungeon?
你怎么不把我扔进地牢？
You spoke with Tyrion in this very brothel
你就在这里和提利昂聊过
on the day that you arrived.
你到达的那天
What did you discuss?
你们讨论了什么？
You think we conspired together?
你认为我们密谋？
What did you discuss?
你们讨论了什么？
The death of my sister.
我姐姐的死
For which you blame me.
你将此事怪罪于我
She was raped and murdered by the Mountain.
她被魔山先奸后杀
The Mountain follows your orders.
魔山听从你的命令
Of course I blame you.
我当然怪罪你
Here I stand unarmed, unguarded.
我在这里手无寸铁
Should I be concerned?
我是不是该害怕？
You are unarmed and unguarded because you know me better than that.
你手无寸铁，是因为你清楚我还不至于
I am a man of reason.
我是理性的人
If I cut your throat today,
今天割了你的喉咙…
I will be drawn and quartered tomorrow.
明天就死无全尸
Men at war commit all kinds of crimes
战争中的人犯下各种罪行
without their superiors' knowledge.
他们的上司不一定知道
So you deny involvement in Elia's murder?
所以你否认和伊莉亚的死有关？
Categorically.
绝对地
I would like to speak with the Mountain.
我要和魔山谈谈
I'm sure he would enjoy speaking with you.
我肯定他会喜欢和你谈
He might not enjoy it as much as he thinks he would.
不一定如他想象的
I could arrange for this meeting.
我可以安排这次会面
But you want something in return.
但你想要回报
There will be a trial for my son.
我儿子将会被审判
And as custom dictates,
按照律例…
three judges will render a verdict.
三个法官会形成最后的判决
I will preside.
我会主持
Mace Tyrell will serve as the second judge.
梅斯·提利尔将是第二法官
I would like you to be the third.
我想让你当第三法官
Why?
为什么？
Not long ago, the Tyrells sided with Renly Baratheon.
不久前，提利尔家和蓝礼·拜拉席恩联手
Declared themselves enemies of the throne.
自宣为是王位的敌人
Now they are our strongest allies.
现在他们是我们强大的盟友
Well, you made the Tyrell girl a queen.
你让提利尔加的姑娘变成了王后
Asking me to judge at your son's trial isn't quite as tempting.
邀我做审判你儿子的法官不怎么诱人
I will also invite you to sit on the small council
我还将邀请你加入御前议会
to serve as one of the new king's principal advisors.
作为新国王的首席顾问
I never realized you had such respect for Dorne, Lord Tywin.
没想到你这么重视多恩，泰温大人
We are not the Seven Kingdoms until Dorne returns to the fold.
多恩不投靠，不成其为七大王国
The king is dead. The Greyjoys are in open rebellion.
国王已死，葛雷乔伊公开叛乱
A wildling army marches on the Wall.
野人大军正向长城挺进
And in the East, a Targaryen girl has three dragons.
在东方，坦格利安家的女孩已有3条龙
Before long, she will turn her eyes to Westeros.
不久，她的目光就会转向维斯特洛
Only the Dornish managed to resist
只有多恩人曾设法抵抗过…
Aegon Targaryen and his dragons.
伊耿·坦格利安和他的群龙
You're saying you need us?
你是说，你需要我们？
That must be hard for you to admit.
你一定很难承认
We need each other.
我们需要对方
You help me serve justice to the king's assassins
你帮我还国王的死以公正
and I will help you serve justice to Elia's.
我帮你还伊莉亚以公正
Podrick.
波德瑞克
Apologies for the stench.
抱歉，很臭
I brought you some wine, my lord, but they took it from me.
我给你带酒来了，大人，被他们拿走了
A noble effort.
精神可嘉
They didn't find the candles, though.
但他们没发现蜡烛
A quill, some parchment,
一支笔，一些羊皮纸
duck sausage, almonds,
鸭肉肠，杏仁
and some hard cheese.
还有一些硬奶酪
You're a good lad.
你真是个好小伙
Any word of Shae?
有雪伊的消息吗？
I've heard nothing, my lord.
我尚未收到，大人
I suppose that's a good thing.
我想这应该是好事
What are they saying about me out there?
他们在外面怎么说我？
You're to stand trial in a fortnight
你在两周后会接受审判
for murdering the king.
罪名是弑君
Do you believe I murdered Joffrey?
你相信我杀了乔佛里吗？
No, my lord.
不，大人
You didn't?
你没杀？
No. Gods, no.
诸神啊，当然没有
The world is a better place without him,
世界没他更好
but I had nothing to do with it.
但我是清白的
I would like to think
我愿意这么想…
if I were arranging a royal assassination,
如果要我安排刺杀国王…
I'd plan it in such a way that I wouldn't be standing there
我会密谋让自己站在那里…
gawking like a fool when the king died.
傻愣地看着国王死
Trial in a fortnight.
两周后审判
Have they announced the judges yet?
<i>宣布法官了吗？</i>
- Your father. - Of course.
- 你父亲
- 那是当然
Mace Tyrell.
梅斯·提利尔
Who will vote exactly as my father tells him to vote.
他会按我父亲的意愿投票
And Prince Oberyn of Dorne.
还有多恩的奥柏伦亲王
Oberyn?
奥柏伦？
Give it to my father.
真佩服我父亲
He never fails to take advantage of a family tragedy.
他善于从我们的家族不幸中捞取资本
I'm supposed to get a list of names from you, my lord.
我应该从你这儿拿个名单，大人
Anyone who might testify on your behalf.
替你作证的人
Oh, I can call my own witnesses?
噢，我可以召自己的证人？
How generous of them.
<i>他们还真慷慨</i>
Very well, my wife. Sansa.
很好，我妻子，珊莎
My lord, she's gone.
大人，她走了
Gone?
走了？
No one's seen her since the wedding.
<i>婚礼后没人再见过她</i>
You don't think she...
你不会以为她…
No one had more cause to kill Joffrey than Sansa,
<i>没人比珊莎更有动机杀了乔佛里…</i>
but the girl is no assassin.
但这姑娘可不会杀人
Whoever killed the king wanted me to lose my head for it.
不管谁是杀国王的凶手，都想让我偿命
And with my wife's disappearance, it makes me seem that much more guilty.
我妻子一消失，我就更显得有罪
- Podrick. - Yes, my lord?
- 波德瑞克？
- 是，大人
- They'll be following you now. - Who will?
- 他们会一直跟着你
- 谁？
I don't know. They. They. The ominous they.
不知道，他们，他们，邪恶的他们
The man pulling the strings. Or woman. My father.
幕后扯线的人，或女人，我父亲
Maybe Joffrey was too much work for him.
也许乔佛里让他吃不消
Sweet Tommen will be so much easier to handle.
可爱的托曼更容易摆布
Whenever something bad happens to me,
不管我后果如何…
I assume it's my sister that had a hand in it.
我想我的姐姐一定脱不开干系
But say what you will of Cersei,
<i>可不论怎么说我姐姐…</i>
she loves her children.
她真爱她的孩子
She is the only one
她是唯一一个…
I'm certain had nothing to do with this murder.
我可以肯定与谋杀无关的人
Which makes it unique
是个特例…
as King's Landing murders go.
就君临的谋杀案而言
Any other witnesses, my lord?
其他的证人呢，大人？
Varys could vouch for me if he dared.
瓦里斯敢的话，也会为我说话
He's already been called as a witness for the queen.
他已经被指名为太后的证人了
Of course. Fetch Bronn. I have a job for him.
当然，找波隆来，我有任务给他
I've already asked, my lord.
我问过了，大人
- They won't let him see you. - Why not?
- 他们不让他见你
- 为什么？
They say he's a known cutthroat and your close associate.
他们说他是有名的冷血，你的搭档
He's under investigation himself.
他自己都在被调查
And my brother?
我哥哥呢？
Will they at least allow me to see Jaime?
他们至少让我见见詹姆吧？
I'll ask, my lord.
我会问的，大人
There's something else, my lord.
还有一件事，大人
A man, I didn't know his face,
有个人，面生的
he came to ask if I'd testify against you.
过来问我会不会指证你
Said I'd be named Ser Podrick Payne
说会授予我波德瑞克·派恩爵士
if I told the judges you'd bought a poison called the Strangler.
只要我告诉法官，你买了名叫“扼死者”的毒药
Ser Podrick Payne?
波德瑞克·派恩爵士？
Has a nice ring to it. What did you tell him?
这个头衔不错，你怎么说？
I didn't tell them anything, my lord.
我什么也没说，大人
Are you going to accept their offer?
你打算接受他的条件吗？
My lord.
我的大人
Testifying against me wasn't a suggestion.
指证我不是个建议
If they can't tempt you with honey,
如果他们用软的不行…
they'll choose something less sweet.
他们会来硬的
You've been good to me, my lord.
你一直待我不错，大人
Pod, the trial's in a fortnight.
波德，离审判还有两周
They'll want an answer before that.
他们在那之前就要求答复
I already gave them an answer, my lord.
我已经答复了，大人
I will not have you dying on my behalf.
我不会让你因我而死
Do you hear me? If I have to take
你听到了吗？如果我要…
that long walk to the executioner's block,
走上那漫长的行刑之路…
I don't want to see your head already mounted.
我不想看到你的人头已经高悬
- My lord. - Pod, I am giving you an order.
- 大人
- 波德，这是命令
Go and find my brother. Tell him I need him.
去找我哥哥，告诉他我要见他
And get yourself out of King's Landing
你自己赶快离开君临城…
before it's too late.
趁还来得及
Pod!
波德！
This is farewell.
就此别过了
Farewell, my lord.
告别了，大人
Pod.
波德
There has never lived a more loyal squire.
从未有你这么衷心的侍从了
Mother says it's time to eat.
妈妈说，该吃饭了
What's she got boiling? Wait. Wait. Let me guess.
她煮了什么？等等，让我猜猜
- Potatoes. - Potatoes.
- 土豆
Well, no one boils a potato better than your mom.
没人比你妈妈煮土豆更好吃
Has she got--
她有没有…
The wildlings!
<i>野人！</i>
Guymon!
盖蒙！
Hide.
藏起来！
Hide!
You know how to get to Castle Black?
你知道怎么去黑城堡吗？
Yes. Yes.
知道，知道
Those your parents?
那是你的双亲吗？
Open your eyes.
睁开眼睛
I'm going to eat them.
我要吃了他们
Do you hear me?
听到了吗？
I'm going to eat your dead mama
我要吃了你死去的妈妈
and I'm going to eat your dead papa.
和你死去的爸爸
Go tell the crows at Castle Black.
去黑城堡告诉乌鸦们
We need to teach them a lesson about the way we deal with their kind.
<i>我们得给他们一个教训</i>，<i>教教他们我们是如何处置乌鸦的</i>
Aye! Aye!
<i>是！是！</i>
Three dozen bodies with slit throats
<i>三打割破喉咙的尸体</i>
tossed off the top of the Wall.
<i>从长城上抛下</i>
Seems like that would be a good lesson.
那倒是个不错的教训
Aye!
是！
If we go after them, we'll be giving them what they want.
如果我们跟着他们，就中他们下怀了
They want to draw us out,
他们想引我们出来
pick us off a few at a time.
一次干掉几个
We have just over 100 men.
我们只有100多人
And that's including stewards and builders.
包括管家和工人
And me. We can't afford to lose a single man.
还有我，我们不能损失任何一个人
We must remember our first responsibility.
我们必须记住我们的首要责任
We are the watchers on the Wall.
我们是长城的守卫者
There's got to be a way to protect them.
必须想办法保护平民
You're a champion of the common people, Lord Snow.
你是为平民而战的斗士，雪诺大人
What do you say to Brother Pyp's proposition?
<i>你认为派普兄弟的提议如何？</i>
Mance Rayder is coming.
曼斯·雷德就要来了
If the wildlings breach the Wall,
一旦野人突破长城
they'll roll over everything and everyone for 1,000 miles
他们会屠戮1000英里内的所有生命
before they reach an army that can stop them.
军队根本来不及阻止他们
We need to shore up Castle Black
我们要守住黑城堡
and we need to defend the Wall.
我们要保卫长城
That is our job.
<i>这是我们的职责</i>
Rangers returning.
游骑兵回来了
Help him.
帮帮他
Thought you'd have blue eyes by now.
还以为你的眼睛已经变蓝了
What took you so long?
怎么去了这么久？
- We were held up. - By what?
- 我们被阻拦了
- 被什么阻拦？
Chains.
锁链
We were guests of the mutineers at Craster's Keep.
我们在卡斯特堡是反叛者的客人
- And the mutineers stayed? - They're not going anywhere.
- 反叛者还在那里？
- 他们不会离开的
They've got Craster's food and his wives.
他们已经得到了卡斯特的食物和他的妻子们
Poor girls.
<i>可怜的女孩们</i>
Never thought they'd miss their daddy.
从没料到会想念她们的父亲
Karl's running things now.
现在卡尔是老大
He's the one who put a knife through Craster's mouth.
是他一刀刺穿卡斯特的喉咙
We need to ride north and kill them all.
我们得北上杀了他们
We just went over this, boy.
这里的事刚结束，小子
- Justice can wait. - It's not about justice.
- 正义可以等待
- 这不是正义的问题
I told the wildlings we had over 1,000 men at Castle Black alone.
我告诉过野人黑城堡有1000多名守卫者
Karl and the others know the truth as well as we do.
卡尔和其他人都跟我们一样知道真相
How long do you think they'll keep that information to themselves
等野人把他们的指甲拔下来
when the wildlings are peeling their fingernails off?
你认为他们还能不开口？
Mance has all he needs to crush us, he just doesn't know it yet.
曼斯已经能摧毁我们了，只是他自己还不知道
As soon as he gets his hands on them, he will.
一旦他抓到他们，他就知道了
Then he'll throw his full strength at us.
那时他就会全力对付我们
And even if every one of us kills 100 wildlings,
即使我们每个人能杀死100个野人
there's still not a thing we can do to stop them.
我们仍无法阻止他们
I don't think I can kill 100 wildlings.
我不认为我能杀死100个野人
Are they attacking?
<i>他们在袭击吗？</i>
A single rider.
<i>只有一名骑士</i>
A champion of Meereen.
<i>弥林的头号勇士</i>
They want you to send your own champion against him.
<i>他们想让您派一名斗士与他搏斗</i>
What is he doing?
他在干什么？
I believe he means to...
我觉得他是想…
He says that we're an army of men without man parts.
他说我们军队的男人没有男人的器官
He claims you are no woman at all, but a man who...
他说您根本不是女人，而是…
hides his cock in his own asshole.
把老二藏进屁眼的男人
Ignore him, Your Grace. These are meaningless words.
别理他，陛下，这些话毫无意义
They're not meaningless
如果你攻取的城里一半的人听进去了
if half the city you intend to take is listening to them.
这些话就不是毫无意义
I have something to say to the people of Meereen.
我有话要对弥林的人民说
First, I will need this one to be quiet.
首先，我要这个人安静下来
Do I have a champion?
我有斗士吗？
<i>请赐予我这个荣耀，龙之母</i>
<i>我定不负您所望</i>
<i>你是无垢者的领袖</i>
<i>我不能拿你冒险</i>
Your Grace, I've won more single combats than any man alive.
陛下，我赢过的战斗比任何在世的人都多
Which is why you must remain by my side.
所以你必须留在我身边
I've been by your side longer than any of them, Khaleesi.
我在你身边比他们任何人都久，卡丽熙
Let me stand for you today as well.
今天也让我替你效力你吧
You are my most trusted advisor,
你是我最信任的顾问
my most valued general, and my dearest friend.
我最尊敬的司令官，也是我最亲爱的朋友
I will not gamble with your life.
我不会拿你的命冒险
I was the last to join your army.
我是最后加入军队的
I'm not your general or a member of your Queensguard
我不是你的司令官，也不是你女王铁卫的一员
or the commander of your Unsullied.
或者是无垢者的指挥官
My mother was a whore. I come from nothing.
我母亲是个妓女，我生来卑贱
And before long, I will return to nothing.
不久之后，也将死得卑微
Let me kill this man for you.
让我为你杀了这人
Very well.
很好
You have quite an audience.
你有很多观众
Make it worth their while.
别让他们失望
He is very brave, Your Grace.
他很勇敢，陛下
Yes, win or lose,
是的，无论输赢
as long as the whole city is watching.
<i>全城的人都在看</i>
You sure you don't want a horse?
你确定不要马？
Why would I want a horse?
<i>我为什么要马？</i>
Horses are faster than men.
马比人快
Horses are dumber than men.
马比人愚钝
我是丹妮莉丝·风暴降生
关于我，你们的主人们也许说了谎话
也许不曾提及
没关系
我对他们无话可说
我只跟你们说话
我先去了阿斯塔波
阿斯塔波曾经的奴隶
现在站在我身后
自由了
然后我去了渊凯
渊凯曾经的奴隶
现在也站在我身后
也自由了
现在我到了弥林
我不是你们的敌人
你们的敌人站在你们身边
你们的敌人偷走你们的孩子并杀害他们
你们的敌人只会给你们锁链，苦难
和命令
我不会命令你们
我给你们选择
我会让你们的敌人尝尝他们应得的
前进！
发射
-=TLF字幕组=-
谢谢观赏
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://weibo.com/tlfsubs
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/